using paper notes when the rest of the world moves to digital currency? Another example from my hometown in Philadelphia: I recently went to the public library there, and they are facing an existential crisis. Public funding is dwindling, they have to reduce their footprint to stay open and stay relevant, and so one of the ways they're going about this is digitizing a number of the books and moving them to the cloud. This is great for most kids. Right? You can check out books from home, you can research on the way to school or from school, but these are really two big assumptions, that one, you have access at home, and two, that you have access to a mobile phone, and in Philadelphia, many kids do not. So what does their education experience look like in the wake of a completely cloud-based library, what used to be considered such a basic part of education? How do they stay competitive? A final example from across the world in East Africa: there's been a huge movement to digitize land ownership rights, for a number of reasons. Migrant communities, older generations dying off, and ultimately poor record-keeping have led to conflicts over who owns what. And so there was a big movement to put all this information online, to track all the ownership of these plots of land, put them in the cloud, and give them to the communities. But actually, the unintended consequence of this has been that venture capitalists, investors, real estate developers, have swooped in and they've begun buying up these plots of land right out from under these communities, because they have access to the technologies and the connectivity that makes that possible. So that's the common thread that connects these examples, the unintended consequences of the tools and the technologies that we make. As engineers, as technologists, we sometimes prefer efficiency over efficacy. We think more about doing things than the outcomes of what we are doing. This needs to change. We have a responsibility to think about the outcomes of the technologies we build, especially as they increasingly control the world in which we live. In the late '90s, there was a big push for ethics in the world of investment and banking. I think in 2014, we're long overdue for a similar movement in the area of tech and technology. So, I just encourage you, as you are all thinking about the next big thing, as entrepreneurs, as CEOs, as engineers, as makers, that you think about the unintended consequences of the things that you're building, because the real innovation is in finding ways to include everyone. Thank you. (Applause)
que usa dinero de papel cuando el resto del mundo mude a digital? Otro ejemplo de mi ciudad natal, Filadelfia: recientemente fui allí a la biblioteca pública, y están teniendo una crisis existencial. La financiación pública está bajando, deben reducir su presencia para seguir abiertos y relevantes, y una forma de hacer esto es digitalizar varios libros y moverlos a la nube. Es magnífico para los chicos, ¿verdad? Puede retirar libros desde casa, puede investigar yendo y viniendo del colegio, pero estas son dos grandes suposiciones, primero, que tiene acceso en casa, segundo, que tiene acceso en el móvil, y en Filadelfia, muchos chicos no los tienen. Así que, ¿cómo será su experiencia educativa en una biblioteca basada completamente basada en la nube que antes era una parte básica de su educación? ¿Cómo se mantendrán competitivos? Un ejemplo final desde África Este: hay un gran movimiento para digitalizar derechos de propiedad de tierra, por varias razones. Comunidades migratorias, viejas generaciones que mueren, y básicamente un mal manejo de registros ha llevado a conflictos sobre propiedad. Así que hay un gran movimiento para poner esta información en línea, y rastrear la propiedad de estos lotes de tierra, llevarlos a la nube y entregarlos a las comunidades. Pero realmente, la consecuencia accidental de esto ha sido que inversores de riesgo, y constructores de finca raíz, se han precipitado a comprar estos lotes de tierra por encima de estas comunidades, porque tienen acceso a las tecnologías y la conectividad que las hace posibles. Este es el denominador común que conecta estos ejemplos, las consecuencias accidentales de los aparatos y las tecnologías que creamos. Como ingenieros, como tecnólogos, a veces preferimos eficiencia a eficacia. Pesamos más en hacer cosas que en los resultados de lo que hacemos. Esto debe cambiar. Tenemos la responsabilidad de pensar en los resultados de las tecnologías, especialmente cuando cada vez controlan más el mundo en que vivimos. A finales de los 90 había una gran presión por ética en el mundo financiero y bancario, Pienso que en el 2014 se ha retrasado un movimiento similar en el área de tecnología. Así que los animo a pensar en la siguiente gran cosa, como emprendedores, gerentes, ingenieros y creadores, a pensar acerca de las consecuencias accidentales de las cosas que estamos creando, porque la verdadera innovación es encontrar formas de incluir a todos. Gracias. (Aplausos)